<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on SharePoint Uncovered</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on SharePoint Uncovered</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:17:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint Custom Scripts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sharepoint-custom-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:17:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sharepoint-custom-scripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Microsoft is proc&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Introduction to SharePoint “custom scripts”&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;In SharePoint, “custom scripts” broadly refers to client‑side code added to pages. Historically, this was common in classic SharePoint experiences and early SharePoint Online, but Microsoft has steadily constrained it to reduce risk; modern team/communication sites, OneDrive, and even the root site block custom scripts by default. Microsoft’s guidance encourages migrating Script Editor–style solutions to the SharePoint Framework (SPFx), which is supported on modern pages and designed for durable, governance‑friendly client‑side development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SharePoint User Id Mismatch Issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/user-id-mismatch-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 08:19:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/user-id-mismatch-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A common issue in SharePoint, known as &lt;strong&gt;User ID Mismatch&lt;/strong&gt;, occurs when a user account is deleted from the directory and later recreated with the same UPN (User Principal Name). This often happens when an employee is rehired or returned from a long leave or when a common name like &lt;em&gt;John Smith&lt;/em&gt; is reused. In short, reusing a username in the directory can trigger a User ID Mismatch in SharePoint.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 08:46:40 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-the-microsoft-365-blog&#34;&gt;Introduction to the Microsoft 365 Blog&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is dedicated to the practical side of Microsoft 365 in enterprise environments, with the focus on SharePoint and its surrounding technologies - Search, Copilot, Purview, Teams, OneDrive, Viva Engage, Entra etc. Drawing from nearly 20 years of hands-on experience — from SharePoint on-prem to SharePoint Online — I share lessons learned, governance strategies, automation techniques, and tenant-wide optimization practices. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re an engineer, architect, or IT leader, you&amp;rsquo;ll find actionable insights on managing large-scale SharePoint deployments, navigating Microsoft 365 integrations, and staying ahead in a rapidly evolving collaboration landscape. No buzzwords, no politics — just real SharePoint engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
